Guide to the Frank L. Borchardt papers UA.29.02.0235
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frank L. Borchardt papers
1971-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Borchardt, Frank L.
UA.29.02.0235
28 Linear Feet
Personal and professional papers. Some subjects include: Calis (computer aided language instruction); Calico presentations and manuals; NSA contracts and proposals; German Department administrative materials; Duke Language Tool kit.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Historical Note
Frank L. Borchardt joined Duke University's Department of Germanic Languages and Literature in 1971. He became chair of the department in 1982 and served in that capacity until 1991. Borchardt worked in two principal areas: Early Modern German Culture, and Educational Technology. He was a pioneer in the use of computer technology in language instruction, and he was instrumental in the creation of CALICO (the Computer Assisted Learning and Instructional Consortium). He edited the CALICO Journal from 1991 to 1997.
Collection Overview
Personal and professional papers. Some subjects include: Calis (computer aided language instruction); Calico presentations and manuals; NSA contracts and proposals; German Department administrative materials; Duke Language Tool kit.
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is unprocessed and may require screening, arrangement, and/or rehousing before use.
- Accession UA2007.0046, 1
  - Class/Conference materials (Box 1)
  - Calico/Calis, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - China, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Calico: Hungary, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Calis contracts, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - NSA, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Minnie Kenny Folder (Box 2)
  - Travel (Box 2)
  - Calico/Calis manual and materials, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Coursework, 2000-2007 (Box 4)
  - Instructional Technology (Box 4)
  - German Department administrative materials (Box 4)
  - Book files, 1990s (Box 5)
  - DLIR (Box 5)
  - Symposium materials (Box 5)
  - Calico related correspondence (Box 5)
  - Calis demo VHS (Box 5)
  - Administrative (Box 6)
  - Class materials (Box 6)
  - State of Apocalyptic Thought book draft (Box 6)
  - Calis (Box 7)
  - Misc. electronic media to be evaluated (Box 7)
  - German Department (Box 8)
  - Calis (Box 8)
  - Calis/Calico (Box 9)
  - Desk files (Box 10)
  - DUCAL (Box 10)
  - DLIR (Box 10)
  - Personnel German Department (Box 10)
  - Course materials (Box 10)
  - Calis/Calico (Box 11)
  - Duke Language Tool kit (Box 11)
  - A-I Filing Cabinet: correspondence, some staff/personnel files (Box 12)
  - J-W filing cabinet (Box 13)
  - NSA (Box 14)
  - German Department (Box 14)
  - Calico presentations (Box 15)
  - Calico presentations (Box 16)
  - German Department materials (Box 16)
  - Calico presentations (Box 17)
  - Calico presentations and manuals (Box 18)
  - NSA contracts and proposals (Box 19)